DEEPA GM

+91 9591557541 deepageenakeri.m01@gmail.com Bangalore, Karnataka

Software QA with **6.5** years of experience in performing functional testing, integration testing, system testing ,Regression testing and strong knowledge of the **Agile**, **SDLC**, **STLC** and **QA** testing process. Experienced in testing Client/Server Web-based and mobile based applications. Experienced in participating in entire QA life Cycle-Designing, Development and execution of the entire QA process.**5.5** year of Experience in Automation Testing. Efficient in writing the Test Plan based on business requirements. Having 3 years of experience in Python .Well versed with **Writing Test Cases**, **Test Case Reviews**, **Test Execution**, **Bug Reporting** and **Tracking**.

SKILLS

- **Software Languages:** Basic Java, C, .net, Python
- **SDLC Methodologies:** Agile-Scrum Framework, Waterfall, SDLC.
- **Software Testing:** Manual Testing concepts And Automation using Java with selenium ,Python and .net with Coded UI,API Automation.
- Tools: JIRA (Bug Tracking Tool), QC, TestRail (Test Management Tool), TFS,katalon studio.
- Operating System: Windows family, Linux, MacOS, RHEL, ESXi, VMware, Vsphere, Vcenter server.
- S/E Methodologies: Functional Testing, Regression Testing, Smoke testing, Sanity testing, UI testing, Adhoc testing and Compatibility testing, load testing.
- Application: MS Project, MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science and Engineering, 2016 with 68.56% aggregate.

PESIT (Shivamogga), Visvesvaraya Technological University – Bengaluru

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

McAfee - Computer Security Company

Software Development Engineer in Test (April 2023 – Present)

Project Name: Mcafee Antivirus Software - Real protect Module

Team Size: 10

About the Projects:

Mcafee Real protect is an antivirus software which is used to detect malware in computer or malware file which is downloaded from website, email and from other source and this RP module mainly works on detecting malware and removing it from system. Which uses cloud Machine Learning module to detect malware.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Involving in discussions with POs
- Writing Test cases and Reviewing test cases as well as performing testing
- Writing, Executing & Reviewing test cases & automation scripts.
- Responsible for providing estimations to the test scenarios for automation.
- Providing on time updates to the lead/manager
- Taking part in daily Standup meetings
- Being part of Production release support team
- Providing testing support for various other teams
- Collaborating with team for on-time delivery

Ernst & Young

Senior Consultant (April 2020 – April 2023)

Project Name: Discrete Demand Draft

Team Size: 1 -for automation

About the Projects:

Discrete Demand draft is considering the orders and calculating the taxes for each product ordered after raising quote .This software is used to get product and peripheral details and placing orders.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Involving in discussions with POs
- Reviewing test cases & performing testing
- Automated software using selenium in katalon studio .
- Automated API testing in katalon studio using groovy language.
- Automated to get data from DB in katalon studio using SQL.
- Writing, Executing & Reviewing test cases & automation scripts.
- Responsible for providing estimations to the test scenarios for automation.
- Providing on time updates to the lead/manager
- Taking part in daily Standup meetings
- Being part of Production release support team
- Providing testing support for various other teams
- Collaborating with team for on-time delivery

Project Name: Dell GII

Team Size: 6

About the Projects:

Sales Order Web & desktop applications that handle Dell orders

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Involving in discussions with POs
- Reviewing test cases & performing testing
- Automated Desktop application using .net with Coded UI
- Writing, Executing & Reviewing test cases & automation scripts.
- Responsible for providing estimations to the test stories
- Coordinating with multiple teams for every release across different verticals
- Providing on time updates to the lead/manager
- Taking part in daily Standup meetings
- Being part of Production release support team
- Providing testing support for various other teams
- Collaborating with team for on-time delivery

Schneider Electric India Pvt Ltd

Software Engineer (May 2017 – March 2020)

Project Name: PowerChute Network Edition, Datacenter Expert Software & Data

Center operation software

Team Size: 6

About the Projects:

Software which controls and monitors the different electrical devices in the Datacenter through Network Management Card without any manual intervention.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Involving in discussions with client & end users
- Preparing requirements specifications document
- Working in Agile environment
- Automated Web UI using Java with Selenium.
- Creating Test Plans and Test Strategy documents
- Writing, Executing & Reviewing test cases & automation scripts
- Performing functional & compatibility testing for web and mobile applications
- Performed **compatibility** testing of Software on Operating systems including **virtualization** environment.
- Conducting Defect Prevention & Risk Analysis meetings
- Performing build verification and validation and doing smoke testing on Latest build.
- Worked closely with the Development team, QA teams and members of Management.
- Worked on automating test cases & estimating automation complexity
- Owning different applications and coordinating with the Testing team .
- Coordinating with the Development team throughout the release.
- Handling concurrent projects from End To End.

Achievement: Have handled multiple projects simultaneously under stringent timelines

Personal details:

DOB: 01/06/1994

Residential Address: Deepa GM,Flat C405, Eswar vanamali,Sri krishna garden,

Kothanur, Bangalore 560077

Nationality: Indian.

Alternate Mobile Number: 8217755930

Declaration:

I hereby affirm that all the above information in this document is true to the best of my knowledge.

Thank you.

Deepa GM

Place: Bangalore

Date: 24/09/2023